BRANDON PAXTON

(402) 370-9227 Elkhorn, Nebraska 68022 14paxton@gmail.com github.com/14paxton https://www.paxtonb.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Studied application development with data management and server and web application development. Learned mainframe programming using COBOL, JCL, DB2; IBM technologies using RPG; and web development using VB.net, C#, Java, HTML, CSS, jQuery, PHP.

Experience ranging from mainframe COBOL programming to Java and Microservice architecture. Proficient in Java, C#, Javascript, SQL/MySQL, Kotlin, and Groovy languages and Grails, Spring, MVC5, and Core frameworks; along with a solid academic background in computer information systems; excellent analytical and problem-solving skills; able to handle multiple projects in a fast-paced, deadline-oriented environment.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Aviture

Software Engineer III, June 2023 - Present

- Software Development with Secret level Government clearance in The Technology Applications Development and Sustainment (TADS) program for the U.S. Air Force
- Work with a cross-functional team to design, develop, test and deploy innovative solutions to a wide range of complex business problems
- Actively participate in all aspects of our agile development process
- Utilize effective debugging techniques to identify and resolve software defects

Veridian Credit Union

Senior Software Developer, January 2023 – May 2023

- Using C#, SqlServer, and ASP.net; Build custom integrations with 3rd party systems/APIs, design code, create relational databases, and test all projects.
- Build chatbots using c#, Google Cloud Platform, and DialogFlow.

Talent Plus

Senior Software Developer, February 2019 - December 2022

- Develop HR consulting software for clients using Groovy(with Grails)
- Create mobile first single page web applications using java, groovy, grails, Spring Boot, Spring Security, javascript, react, node, micronaut, mySQL, redis, apache camel, and Docker
- Develop HR consulting software for clients using Groovy(with Grails)
- Create mobile first single page web applications using java, groovy, grails, Spring Boot, Spring Security, javascript, react, node, micronaut, mySQL, redis, apache camel, and Docker
- Created dynamic library to create forms using react-hook-forms to replace Formik
- Created custom search function component using react-hook-forms and Created an async search and load function that prevented whole table from re-rendering
- Created a customized date range picker in react that worked with the advanced search form I created
- Used Java to create custom HTTP builder service to use a bit stream to retrieve an image stored on an AWS S3 bucket and attach it to an outgoing email using Postmark
- Integrated application with Calendly to add interview times to client calendars

- Integrated application with Microsoft Graph to add interview times to client calendars
- Using hibernate events, set up an async emailing service that is triggered off of new user saves
- Created Microservices using Micronaut, Java, Kotlin utilizing Reactive Hibernate, and Microstreams

Nebraska Office of the Chief Information Officer

Software Developer/IT Applications Administrator, February 2017 – February 2019

- Developed internal website using Java, utilized by our developers, to request new reverse proxies or update an existing one
- Developed a website using Java, Spring Framework, and Hibernate to show records of donations and how they were allocated.
- Using Access Manager create and monitor reverse proxies
- Deploy production applications to TomCat servers
- Manage e-directory by creating and maintaining LDAP scripts
- Created internal website with ASP and SQL Server database for tracking "1-800" numbers and services used by the state
- Created internal website and ticketing system using Java, Spring, and JSF to monitor proxy requests

<u>Dell</u>

Sr. Data Operations Advisor, February 2015 – February 2017

- Created Windows service using C# that removes client reports that have not been accessed in over 60 days from our servers
- Created website and database using .ASP and SQL Server that displays up to date information about managers and supervisors for specific departments
- Created website, database, and service using .ASP, SQL Server, and C# that monitors and shows up-to-date statuses of data files that have been sent or still need to be sent. Prompting emails to the necessary people if data transfers are late.
- Plans, organizes, and coordinates ongoing data center installations and modifications to meet current and future timelines
- Coordinate mainframe batch job schedules.
- Database administrator, deploy SQL scripts and maintain databases on SQL Server
- Change Management, checking and implementing production code through TFS
- Update existing VB.net applications to C#
- Maintained Mainframe applications and data management using DB2, COBOL, and Rex
- Compiled mainframe applications, and ran batch jobs using JCL(Job Control Language)

<u>Nelnet</u>

Senior Technical Representative, Jan 2012 - June 2014

- Interpreted, evaluated, and tested client inquiries and issues pertaining to software; determined appropriate technical function to resolve the problem.
- Troubleshoot computer related problems hindering customers from using company products.
- Documented and tracked status of client inquiries/incidents, coordinated an appropriate response, and followed up to ensure client satisfaction.
- Translated technical details into business relevant language.

EDUCATION

Doane, Lincoln NE

Computer Science

• Emphasis: Application Development

Southeast Community College, Lincoln NE

Computer Information Technology

• Emphasis: Programming and Application Development

University of Nebraska Lincoln, Lincoln NE

BA in Advertising

- Concentration: Business Marketing
- Member of Advertising Club

REFERENCES

- **Dustin Pittak** (Senior Software Engineer) (402) 459-0828
- Nathan Price (Director of Software Development) (402) 202-4137
- **Kevin Vancott** (Software Engineer) (402) 309-9224